Around a month ago, we had taken a look
at Sim AI, another platform for easily
creating AI agents that can automate
anything. In a way, it's like an
open-source Nathan alternative that's
simpler to use, very similar to Nathan,
but not as technical. But some people
are looking for a technical and easy to
use balance. Which is why today I'm back
to showcase a new alternative to both
Nathan and Simei. A workflow automation
and orchestration tool that's open-
source, fully local, and seriously
powerful. It's called Kestra, a fast,
scalable, declarative AI native
orchestration platform where you can
practically automate anything. You may
be wondering what makes Kestra different
from something like Nathan. Well, unlike
Nathan which is an integration first
with a nodebased UI, Castra is
orchestration first which is bringing
infrastructure as a code to data
pipelines infra as well as event-driven
workflows so you can build reliable
automations in a few lines of VM right
from the UI. And you can even have AI
take on this task of doing it for you
which is pretty easy and simple. For
example, let's say you got a load of CSV
files that would normally take hours in
Google Sheet to orchestrate, configure,
as well as calculate different sorts of
formulas. But with Kestre's no code AI
copot, you can give it a prompt as to
what you want to accomplish in plain
natural language. And it builds the
automation for you, handling all the
calculations automatically, the
formatting with a new file. And it will
also even tell you when a new file has
been created by sending you messages
through different platforms if you
require like Slack messages when the
workflow is actually completed. And
remember guys, Kestra is open-source and
fully available locally. It's a platform
that blends code flexibility with a
noode UI and it's super easy to get
started. You have 950 plus integrations,
a lot of different services and APIs
available. Uh you can also configure a
lot of things on your own which is
pretty helpful and useful. But to get
started it is super simple. All you need
to have installed beforehand is Docker
Desktop as a prerequisite. You can
install it for whatever operating system
you may have, but if you are going to be
using the Docker method, you can simply
follow through with this quick start
method, which I'll leave a link to in
the description below. There's also a
cloud hosted option, but it's paid, I
believe, and I don't really recommend
you use that cuz you if you have the
ability to use it locally, much better
that way cuz you can access it for free.
So, to get started, just make sure you
have Docker Desktop installed. It's
completely free to install, which I'll
leave a link to in the description
below. Once you have it installed, if
you are using Docker and if you are
looking to get started with it, you can
easily just copy the script over here,
which is a single command that you can
run within your terminal. But there's a
couple of different presets that you can
use if you're on Windows. So, if you're
using PowerShell, you can use this
command set. If you're on Windows and
you're using command prompt, you can use
this. And if you are on Windows and
you're using WSL, you can copy this,
which is something that I'm doing. So,
I'm going to copy this. Make sure I have
Docker Desktop running on my toolbar,
you can check that by opening this up
and see if Docker Desktop is running,
which it is. And now what we can do is
simply open up WSL. And then now we can
paste in this command, which is going to
work on installing Castra locally on our
computer. It's easy as that, guys. Once
it finishes pulling and installing all
the containers, we can then open it up
within our local host. Before we get
started, I just want to mention that you
should definitely go ahead and subscribe
to the world of AI newsletter. I'm
constantly posting different newsletters
on a weekly basis. So, this is where you
can easily get up-to-date knowledge
about what is happening in the AI space.
So, definitely go ahead and subscribe as
this is completely for free. There we
go. We have catcher running locally.
Now, what you got to do first is just
simply create an account so that you can
instantly access Castra locally with
your own authentication. So, simply go
ahead and fill this out. After creating
an account, this is where you're going
to be sent over to the main dashboard of
Kestra where you can now get started and
create your automation flows. Now, what
you want to do first is take a look at
all the different panels. On the main
dashboard is where you can access all
your workflows. You can access all your
flows over here. These are a couple of
tutorial flows that you can actually
readily access and gives you a better
idea of what is happening. You can
execute this AI agent calling flow by
simply starting it up, but we're not
going to be doing that just yet. You
have all your apps where you can build
custom apps with Castra, which is great.
You have executions where you can manage
all of them. Uh see the total runtime as
well as when it was logged. You have a
couple of tests that you can visualize.
name spaces, the KV store which is the
database, secrets where you can manage
all all of your environment keys. You
have blueprints which are templates in a
way that you can readily access uh
whether that's running a specific task
uh triggering something with different
automations and you can even manage
different plugins with 713 plus plugins
which is insane.
But now on the main dashboard, if you
click on create your own workflow from
scratch, you can use the tutorial to
help you build anything. This is where
it's going to teach you what you can do,
all the use cases like where you can
build AI agents, business operations
like automation, sorry, uh business
process, data engineering, etc. We're
going to go ahead and create a simple AI
agent. We're going to click next. And
this is essentially the code editor.
Now, you don't need to write any bit of
code because the AI copilot is something
that you can use. You're just going to
need to configure it within the
application yam file by setting your
Gemini or whatever provider's API key
and then you can simply use it to build
almost anything. But this is where you
can visualize the different nodes of
your automation on the right hand
section. Now, there's also a playground
that you can enable, but you can also
execute it by clicking on this button,
and then you can launch the AI agent
that you're trying to create. Now, it's
going to fail because I haven't set my
API key. But then you can start creating
your new flows and start building
automations exactly from here, but just
take a look at this flow that was
already created, which is the business
automation tutorial. And essentially
this is where it's able to process
anything from your working directory
going to be able to query it and it's
going to process your CSV file and
essentially it's converting the CSV data
to the Google sheet that we had
showcased at the start. Its purpose is
to automate repetitive business tasks
like data processing, notification,
approval. And essentially once you have
set the different configurations within
the execution and edit flow, you're
going to be able to then have it so that
you can execute this flow which is going
to automate this process. So if you
click on execute, it's going to work on
processing the working directory CSV
files. It's going to then query their
prompt which is to create a table in
this case or delete certain features a
part of the CSV file and then from CSV
it will proc it to the Excel Google
sheet. But when you're starting off from
scratch if you're working on the node
code section where you're configuring
each of the nodes just simply define the
ID of the node as well as the
description as to what you're trying to
achieve. But within the flow code this
is where you can configure the YAM file
with AI copilot. This is essentially
where you can just naturally describe
what you want to configure and the AI
will basically take care of the task of
handling, what sort of automation you
want to build, code it out for you and
then you can visualize it over here and
then try it out within the playground
which you can then run as you execute
this task. Here is a data engineering
pipeline. Essentially, it is taking in
dummy data and from here it is
processing it by transforming the data
into a specific pipeline. But what's
happening here is where Castra is
actually fetching the JSON data set from
the remote API and its purpose is to
basically simulate ingesting raw data
from external sources like this dummy
JSON website and from here it is then
transforming the data which Kestra does
autonomously with the AI agents. It runs
a Python script inside this temporary
docker container and its purpose is to
isolate as well as make sure that the
environment is consistent and fully
automated by using these different
debuggers. And then lastly it is the
query which is where it is focusing on
running this SQL like query against the
transformed data that we had sent in and
its purpose is to automate the analytics
after ingesting and transforming that
data. And all of this was fully
controlled with the help of Castra. If
you like this video and would love to
support the channel, you can consider
donating to my channel through the super
thanks option below. Or you can consider
joining our private Discord where you
can access multiple subscriptions to
different AI tools for free on a monthly
basis, plus daily AI news and exclusive
content, plus a lot more. But that was
just a simple overview of what Kestre is
capable of doing. There's so much more
to this, so I highly recommend that you
take a look at it with the links in the
description below. This is something
that's open source, fully local, and
it's a bit more technical, but it gives
you a lot more flexibility as to what
you're trying to achieve with Kestra.
So, make sure you take a look at it with
the links in the description below.
Subscribe to the second channel, join
the newsletter, make sure you subscribe
to the Patreon page to access our
Discord, follow me on Twitter, and
lastly, make sure you guys subscribe to
the YouTube channel. Make sure to turn
on notification bell, like this video,
and please take a look at our previous
videos cuz there's a lot of videos that
you will truly benefit from. But with
that thought, guys, thank you guys so
much for watching. Have an amazing day.
Spread positivity and I'll see you guys
fairly shortly.